<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Walk by the Spirit</title>
    <link>http://walkbythespirit.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Walk by the Spirit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://walkbythespirit.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Train up an Employee</title>
      <link>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/train-up-an-employee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/train-up-an-employee/</guid>
      <description>There is a famous verse in Proverbs 22:6 about raising children. One aspect of this verse was explained to me in the context of employee&amp;rsquo;s the other day.
 &amp;ldquo;Train up a child in the way he should go: and when he is old, he will not depart from it.&amp;rdquo; - Proverbs 22:6
 The part I want to focus on is &amp;ldquo;the way he should go&amp;rdquo;. Notice it doesn&amp;rsquo;t say &amp;ldquo;the way you are going&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judging Others</title>
      <link>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/judging-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/judging-others/</guid>
      <description>We all know that we need to speak truth and point our lies in a loving way. The most loving people also will seek to speak the truth for the purpose of restoring you (as God does) instead of punishing/removing you (as the world does).
The world is quick to execute or imprison people to remove evil as it has no reference for restoration or changing mans heart. However, Christians know the power of God to change man&amp;rsquo;s heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Is</title>
      <link>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/love-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/love-is/</guid>
      <description>To the world, love means emotions and feelings. You can &amp;ldquo;fall into love&amp;rdquo; and you can &amp;ldquo;fall out of love&amp;rdquo;. Love is a force you have no control over that simply provides pleasure.
God&amp;rsquo;s description of love is that of many things (1 Corinthians 13) but especially sacrifice. You can&amp;rsquo;t truly love something without giving something up for it (money, time, comfort). Love is costly: Just ask Jesus.
However, love is also something we make a choice to purse and something that follows us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended Teachers</title>
      <link>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/my-favorite-teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/my-favorite-teachers/</guid>
      <description>I can recommend the following teachers after hearing their knowledge and heart for the Lord. All of them are authors, though John Piper is the most prolific. I have grouped them by the primary activities they are known for: actions or words
Words: - David Platt (Pastor) - John Piper (Pastor) - Alan Hood (Pastor) - Nabeel Qureshi (Debater, Deceased) - Chuck Smith (Pastor, Deceased) - Dan Mohler (Speaker)
Actions: - Francis Chan (Evangelist, Speaker, Compassion Works) - Paul Washer (Missionary, Pastor) - Todd White (Evangelist)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Promised Land</title>
      <link>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/promised-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/promised-land/</guid>
      <description>“Thomas said to him, Lord, we do not know where you go; how can we know the way? Jesus said to him, I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me. - John 14:5-6
 The pattern we see in scripture is one of God leading those who have faith in God. Every important event in scripture is 100% God leading people who seem at best to have no more than a fuzzy idea about where they are even going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesus is our Example</title>
      <link>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/jesus-is-our-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/jesus-is-our-example/</guid>
      <description>If we want to imitate Christ then we have to deny ourselves, take up the cross, and follow him. Perhaps you agree with this, but it means an end to your plans and your choices forever. It means learning how to walk by the Spirit. Never again to walk by the flesh.
Jesus is our example in all things. He never said or did anything but what God told him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowing God&#39;s Spirit</title>
      <link>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/knowing-gods-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/knowing-gods-spirit/</guid>
      <description>In John 14 Jesus tells his disciples that we are to know the Holy Spirit
 “And I will pray the Father, and he shall give you another Comforter, that he may abide with you forever; Even the Spirit of truth; whom the world cannot receive, because it seeth him not, neither knoweth him: but ye know him; for he dwelleth with you, and shall be in you. - John 14:16-17</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bible is not more important than the Holy Spirit</title>
      <link>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/bible-vs-holy-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/bible-vs-holy-spirit/</guid>
      <description>When I think about the Holy Spirit I first think of “the fruit of the Spirit”. But this is wrong. When we think about God we shouldn’t first think about what He gives us - but WHO He is. The Holy Spirit is God’s Spirit. Listening to and obeying the Spirit is listening and obeying God himself.
Remember all the things Jesus taught and did that aren’t written in the Bible?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit Leads Us Into All Truth</title>
      <link>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/spirit-leads-us-into-all-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/spirit-leads-us-into-all-truth/</guid>
      <description>Every prophet in the Old and New Testament, every new truth and turn of the church (from salvation for the gentiles to the missionary journeys), and every important thing period in the bible started with God’s word and leading.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take the salvation of the Gentiles. Despite the prophecies in every book of the bible about their salvation, God gave specific revelation to the early church by His Spirit, that the Gentiles would also share in salvation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/love-our-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://walkbythespirit.org/post/love-our-sin/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;And in those days, when the number of the disciples was multiplied, there arose a murmuring of the Grecians against the Hebrews, because their widows were neglected in the daily ministration. Then the twelve called the multitude of the disciples unto them, and said, It is not reason that we should leave the word of God, and serve tables. Wherefore, brethren, look ye out among you seven men of honest report, full of the Holy Ghost and wisdom, whom we may appoint over this business.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>